Mohammed Anees

Test lead at LionbdrigeTechnology Private Limited

Overall 8+ years of experience as a QA engineer and 4+ years of experience as an automation QA engineer specializing in Agile Scrum, Waterfallmodels. Developed and delivered multiple automation frameworks, defined testing processes for design QA, streamlined automation test cycles.

+91 9094242987

mdanees4242@gmail.com

linkedin.com/in/mohammed-anees-25650a157/

EXPERIENCE

Lionbridge Technology Private Limited, Bangalore, India — *Test Lead*

May 2016 - Present.

Technospark communications Pvt Ltd, Bangalore,India — *Test Engineer*

Dec 2013 - April 2016.

EDUCATION

Madras University College, Chennai, India — B.sc

June 2009 - March 2012

Specialized in Information Technology

Radiance Mat.Hr.Sec, Chennai, India — Mat, HSC

June 2005 - March 2009

Specialized in Mathematics, Physics, and Chemistry

PROJECTS

VMware vSAN(HCI)— HPE

May 2018 - Aug 2021.

- Evaluate the functional and non-functional requirements for test-ability, test cases and use cases for suitability for automation.
- Assist the development of the test automation strategy and focus specifically on maximizing reuse for regression purposes.
- Design, build and execute automated tests to validate applications using Selenium
- Identify regression testing needs and create and maintain an Automated Regression Suite.
- Understanding of overall Testing process and experience in Agile Methodology
- Implement the strategy via developing, coding and executing test case and test script frameworks using automated tools such Selenium.
- Hands-on-experience on configuring Hyper-converged Storage box from the scratch
- Hands-on-experience on creating Storage profile for Synergy blades using HPE One view
- Validating NVMe storage in HPE servers and checking Compatibity in VMware vSAN
- Planning of hardware requirement for the project
- Interaction with the Client team on the project status updates and working with them from the beginning of the project in the Client location.
- Mentoring the Engineers for system configuration and testing

SKILLS

- → Selenium WebDriver with Java, JUnit, TestNG.
- → BDD Cucumber with Java
- → Agile Methodology
- → Firmware testing for Raid controller
- → API Testing
- → Defect management with JIRA,DCPN,Bugzilla,ALM

AWARDS

- ★ STAR award from client
- ★ **SPOT** award from LB.

TOOLS

- Maven
- Git
- Eclipse
- Junit
- ALM
- JIRA
- Jenkins
- Postman
- Selenium WebDriver
- REST-Assured
- Cucumber

Traditional Tape Storage (DAS and SAN)— HPE

May 2016 - April 2018

HPE StoreEver MSL Entry-level Tape Automation products help SMB customers to meet long-term data retention requirements, as well as provide air-gapped data protection from the growing threat of ransomware. The HPE MSL 1/8 autoloader and HPE StoreEver MSL2024 tape library offer broad capacity options including LTO-9, LTO-8, LTO-7, or LTO-6 Ultrium drives. HPE CVTL makes the MSL 1/8 Autoloader and the MSL2024 tape library easy to manage from any location, mitigating the need for remote office IT staff.

Task/Responsibilities

- Understanding the client requirements and project functionalities.
- Executing the test cases (Functional, Regression and Performance Testing)
- Updating Framework functions when needed Developed and executing the Automation Test Scripts
- Preparation of test scenarios/cases/execution and test results.
- Raise, Retest and track defects to closure
- Interact with various involved workstreams to update test and defect status
- Be an active participant in the Daily Stand-ups and Team retrospectives
- Co-ordination of the work of test team members and development team
- Planning of hardware requirement for the project

Mega Raid Product Testing—Promise

December 2013 - May2016

In a typical Storage environment, multiple I/O applications trying to store and retrieve the data will happen, but sometimes data loss may happen the reason might be hardware or power failure. To provide the solution to data loss or to provide redundant data (copy of data) and also to correct medium errors in data, we have a solution by MEGARAID Management. In this, by creating different raid levels based on customer requests we can ensure data is safe all the time without any difficulty.

Task/Responsibilities

- Understanding the client requirements and project functionalities.
- Preparing the Test Cases and execution of Test Cases.
- Configuring zones through Cisco, Brocade, FC switches.
- Responsible for executing RAID Qualification test for all the RAID levels
- Functionality testing, Stress Testing and Regression Testing.
- Performing scalability testing with JBOD's
- Understanding the Test Plan
- Testing of all range of Fiber channels, SAN Storages from Entry level to Highend in all Windows and Non windows Operating System.
- Bug reporting and Tracking.

RESPONSIBILITIES

- Implementation of generic and project-specific libraries.
- Understanding the business requirements of the customer and designing detailed test plans to the best knowledge
- Implementing and maintaining E2E CI infra
- Creating the test verification reports and requirement traceability matrix in detail for results analysis.
- Involved in Gerrit patch reviews.

LANGUAGES

- English
- ☐ Tamil
- Hindi

PERSONAL INFORMATION

Gender: Male Nationality: India Passport: T0743509